RITESH PALLOD

ritesh.pallod7@gmail.com | +91 9763036878 | linkedin.com/in/rpallod/

SUMMARY

Senior Data Engineer who prepares Big Data Applications, manages DS platforms and creates data pipelines. Skilled in Big Data frameworks like Spark, Pig, Hadoop; experienced in building efficient data pipelines to power an ML model & creating models on top of Big Data. Have an excellent understanding of Linux systems & platforms like Kubernetes, Mesos, YARN.

My work is a mix of software engineering, data engineering, platforms & machine learning. What I may lack in years of experience, I gain in hard work, sincerity & passion for technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Glance (part of InMobi Group), Bangalore, India

June 2018 - Current

Senior Data Engineer, Data Sciences

- Cardpress Automatic Content Creation Platform
 - Stitching eight different models together, running in sequence to generate a Card. Time and cost savings translate into business opportunities allowing Glance to launch and scale in new geos. Adding an approval layer for content creators
- ML Serving Platform:
 - Serving of Recommendation Experiments on Kubernetes where Flask & ML serving frameworks were stress-tested to decide the best serving set-up that can serve 17k QPS. MLeap with Java backend was the winner (35x improvement over existing serving framework)

Data Engineer, Data Sciences

- Modelling:
 - User Scoring: Used Spark & VW to capture users' behaviour across four parameters (propensity to transact, interact; frequency, recency scores); utilized InMobi's massive dataset for the same.
- Revenue Forecasting: Built a time series model to forecast ad revenue based on Salesforce and historical data to get weekly, monthly, quarterly predictions for the Business and Finance Team
- Data Engineering:
 - Glance Reporting: A background Spark job which generates heavily aggregated datasets & pushes metrics to Superset & Postgres server such that all kinds of reporting are possible to capture Product health & ML experiments
 - User Feature Store: Feature Engineering using location data, historic activity/traffic features for a billion of users using Pig
 & Falcon
 - Glance Recommendation Engine: Worked on the feature engineering part where TBs of events were utilized to create meaningful features which capture user profile & behavioural pattern on Glance using PySpark
- Platforms
 - Managing and optimizing the DS Platform (Apache Mesos + JupyterHub Setup) to cope with the heavy resource consumption requirements for Data Sciences & Product teams

BMC Software, Pune, India

Intern

July 2017 - March 2018

- BMC ETL & Aggregation Framework
- Developed an ETL tool that was aimed at extracting millions of records from a data-warehouse, performing aggregation functions on it and providing a consolidated, processed result; exempting the client the overhead of processing individual data from the source

EDUCATION

Pune Institute Of Computer Technology, Pune

June 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E) in Computer Engineering; GPA: 3.73/4.00 Electives: Natural Language Processing, Data Mining, Algorithms, Databases

SKILLS

Programming skills:

- Advanced: Python, SQL, Spark
- Technologies/Databases: Hadoop, Hive, Falcon, Mesos, Kubernetes, Django, Azure, ML frameworks

PROJECTS

• Query Based Image Retrieval Tool

 Description: A web application that fetches photos as per the input query. The system works by linking existing photos to the database. The program analyses the photos to identify objects and store them as tags. Images are retrieved based on these tags